Tucson Clinic records, 1927-1986
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Tucson Clinic records, 1927-1986
MS 343
Tucson Clinic
Papers, 1927-1986 (bulk 1951-1986), regarding the business activities of Tucson Clinic, an associated corporation with the Tucson Medical & Surgical Clinic, 1927-1970. Includes Minutes from stockholder meetings; corporation bylaws; contract agreements; legal correspondence with Mesch, Clark and Rothschild law firm; stock purchase and sales agreements; stock certificates; partnership agreements; site drawing plans and building blueprints. Also included are photographs of building interiors and employee gatherings.
1.2 linear feet.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
The Tucson Medical and Surgical Clinic first filed articles of incorporation on July 27, 1927. During the 1950’s and 1960’s the company began a business relationship with the Tucson Clinic, essentially a spin-off corporation, which was officially incorporated in March 1963. These papers outline the formation and growth of the corporation from 1953-1985, until its sale in 1986 to the Thomas Davis Clinic.
Organization
This collection is organized into 2 Subgroups.
Subgroup I: Papers, 1951-1986
Subgroup II: Photographs, 1961-1994
Scope and Content Note
The Papers in the first subgroup include minutes from stockholder meetings, 1955-1982; corporation bylaws, 1951-1982; contract agreements, 1951-1986 and 1927 incorporation agreement; legal correspondence with Mesch, Clark and Rothschild law firm, 1982-1984; stock purchase and sales agreements 1954-1986; stock certificates, 1954-1986; partnership agreements, 1945-1968; site plans and building blueprints, 1953-1985; and newspaper clippings, 1979-1980. This collection contains materials primarily from the years, 1951-1986.
The second subgroup contains color photographs of building interiors/exteriors, employee gatherings and group portraits. Also included are color slides, silver gelatin prints and color negatives. Most photographic materials come from the period, 1961-1985. However, photographs from as recent as 1994 are included. These later prints may reflect employee gatherings from the Thomas Davis Clinic which bought out controlling interest of the Tucson Clinic in 1986.
Access Terms
Thomas Davis Clinic.
Tucson Medical and Surgical Clinic.
Health facilities -- Records.
Health facilities -- Administration.
Medicine, Health -- Arizona -- Tucson.
Medical centers -- Arizona -- Tucson.
Health facilities -- Arizona -- Tucson.
1925-1949
1950-1974
1975-1999
Container List
- Subgroup 1: Papers, 1951-1986
  - Series 1: Business Papers, 1951-1986
    - Minutes and Corporation Records, Copy of 1927 Incorporation Agreement, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, Lease and Incorporation Agreement, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, Corporate Records, 1956-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, Articles of Incorporation, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, Memos, Financial Statements, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Minutes and Bylaws, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Financial Statement, Agreement to Transfer Stock to Thomas-Davis Clinic and Legal Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Legal Correspondence and Documents, Mesch, Clark and Rothschild Attorneys at Law, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Partnership Agreements, 1954-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Stock Certificates and Deed Agreements, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Stock Certificates, 1956-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Series 2: Project Files, 1953-1985
    - Site Plan and Blueprints, 1953-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Building Plans, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Subgroup 2: Photographs, 1961-1994
  - Series 1: Photographs, 1961-1994
    - Photographs, Color Slides, Prints and Color Negatives. Image Totals: 64 color prints; 31 prints, 55 slides and 12 negatives, 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Photographs and Negatives. Image Totals: 70 prints; 24 negatives, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)